MY MAI

my.maithi@gmail.com | Linked In | Github | Website | Contact: 02102354710

SUMMARY

My name is My Mai. I am a Software Engineer with over **7 years** of experience building web applications using modern web technologies, with strong fundamentals in **Ruby on Rails and React**. I am passionate about programming languages and developer tooling and eager to advance my skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, RSpec, React, Redux, React Query, React Testing Library, Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE

MEA Mobile, New Zealand | Web Developer

03/2023 - present

- Developed admin dashboards to enable the content team to manage multiple websites
 efficiently, implementing REST APIs using FeathersJS and building React-based UI components
 to simplify creating and updating webpages.
- Build interactivity templates with React, HTML, and CSS, increasing the marketing team's ability to reach potential users by 100x. Improving load times to under 2 seconds and Lighthouse SEO score of 98.
- Rebuilding the component utilizing Redux's shallowEqual function to optimize the Upload Component improved performance, achieving 100% performance gains.
- Developed a continuous integration pipeline using **GitLab CI**, **AWS SQS**, and **AWS Lambda** to automate email release notifications.
- Collaborated with testers to improve automation tests using Linkinator and Playwright to
 ensure no broken links were present when deploying the website.

SiliconJungles, Singapore | Web Developer

04/2018 - 07/ 2022

- Developed RESTful APIs using Ruby on Rails for the eTips digital tipping application, focusing primarily on shopper-related endpoints. Implemented features allowing shoppers to manage user profiles, configure payment settings, update country-specific currencies, review payment histories, and track transactions efficiently.
- Developed a mobile application that collects data from wearable devices and tracking apps to
 provide actionable insights. Utilized React Native and ng-chart to create a hexagonal chart. This
 feature has improved how 20K active users discover how their lifestyle influences their
 cognitive health and performance.

Maintained a survey web application used by USA universities. Migrating functions from **jQuery** to React and State Machine. Implemented new features that improved web functionalities for more than 9.8K created surveys and 320K responses.

Finology Sdn Bhd, Malaysia | Fullstack Developer

07/2016 - 04/2018

- Developed and maintained **RESTful APIs** for the Loanplus product using the **Ruby on Rails** framework to improve features for over **60,000 users**. Additionally, I utilized tools such as Postman to test and debug APIs.
- Developed and generated reporting documentation by creating custom Rails Rake tasks to parse CSV files, enabling the Custcare team to efficiently manage customer data, lawyers, bankers, sales developers, and loan projects.
- Developed highly interactive and customized UIs using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS to improve the functionality of web applications. Standardized all output with a responsive, cross-browser compatible.

OPENSOURCE

- Hanami (Lotus) is a Ruby framework. I contributed to this framework on 3 issues:
 - Introduce Lotus.root: https://github.com/hanami/hanami/pull/213
 - Refactor update timestamp: https://github.com/hanami/model/pull/182
 - Update updated at for Hanami: https://github.com/hanami/model/pull/176
- Author of **React Native** react-native-toggle-element package modifies the toggle button, with 6000+ weekly downloads. Utilized React Native Testing Library to test the UI component and integrated it with GitHub Actions.
- Spendy Tracker, a side project that leverages the OpenAl API to analyze receipts and summarize spending based on category and period. Using Rails, React, and Redux.

ACTIVITIES

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner from Amazon Web Services (AWS) in 2023
- I was a speaker at Ruby Conference Malaysia 2017. My topic was "Best practices of SVG on Ruby on Rails."

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Information Technology, 06/2013 Da Nang University, Vietnam

GPA: 3.06 / 4.00